lethal. In fact, there have been cases of
doses of caffeine. This means that
people in the world per year. Instead,
Psychedelics seem to me
superimposed by the potential
such a huge therapeutic effect they have and
The investigation is ongoing. And what about you?
What do psychedelics do to the brain?
That's a very good question, it's the
Psychedelics are capable of breaking
deeply ingrained cyclical thoughts
how can an addiction be in a
"Person" is used a lot, for example,
trauma treatment. This helps the
patient in their therapeutic process, a
long therapeutic process, but the
What psychedelics do is shorten that
therapeutic process and condense it because
make the effect or effectiveness of
that psychotherapy is greater. Why not
We delved a little into psychedelics. You
You call it a psychedelic renaissance in your
book. What [music] does that imply? That
means? Okay, so let's see, and
What defines a drug? What is
a drug?
Well, a psychoactive drug is a
substance that when we introduce it into
the organism interacts with the
receptors that we have in neurons
of the central nervous system and produces
changes in our psyche, huh, that
These changes can be at the level of
emotional, at a psychological level, at a
behavioral and at the level of perception, right?
In other words, it changes how we perceive the
things.
This means there are many
substances, uh, to this day that
We consume it quite frequently
In general, I mean, human beings,
such as coffee, alcohol, the
tobacco, and many, many medications,
especially psychotropic drugs, which are
psychoactive substances, which are drugs
And there are many others, well, maybe
They're close to having effects, huh?
in that field, such as sugar
that we were coming
As I mentioned before, they don't quite reach the level of
For example, it has the characteristic
harmful to health. But it is true that
It is also important to take into account
that these two characteristics, the
Addiction and the damage to health are not
intrinsic characteristics of all
drugs. In other words, there are many drugs,
They can be addictive and they can be
harmful to health, and that's true, but
There are many others that do not have these.
characteristics and are undoubtedly
Psychoactive drugs, right?
Mm, I understand we're talking about the
Psychedelic, right? Because we don't put
First of all, Anton, in context, me
You tell a little about the families of the
drugs, then we'll get into psychedelics
and all that.
Yes, well, I really enjoy teaching one
graph e that we have hanging in
Drogopedia, on the channels in which
I do outreach about drugs, which is
basically the drug cycle. is
a very simple model to understand
how are the different eh structured
families, let's say, of drugs that
They exist, don't they? There are about seven families of
main drugs, uh, for example, the
depressant drugs, which are drugs to the
which includes, for example, alcohol,
to which GHB belongs or the
Benzadepines, which are so widely used in
medicine to treat anxiety. Are
drugs that reduce the activity of
central nervous system, which disinhibit
and that, well, they may have a problem with
be very addictive or very toxic, even
Lethal, aren't they? Tenemos luego, por
For example, opioid drugs, which are
subjective, for example, the sensation,
sorry, from pain, both physical and
sometimes emotional. And this makes them
also quite addictive substances,
produce a very large response of
dopamine, they can be very, very
hooking, highly addictive, and in doses
High temperatures can be very lethal, in fact
They stop breathing and make the
People often die because of it.
suffocation, right? Not because of not breathing. of
of pioids
Opioids, for example, would be, uh, from
drugs derived from mapola
opium, morphine, codeine,
Thevaine, to synthetic drugs that we have
created by us, as they can be, by
For example, fentanyl, and nitacenes.
Heroin would be a semi-synthetic
because it looks like it, that is, it's a
a substance very similar to morphine
natural. It's simply a change.
Small, but come on, they are substances
to soothe the pain. In fact, if
If we ran out of opioids, it would be a
a very serious problem for medicine
today, because pain management
uh [snort] practically the pains
strong, eh, it can't be done without
Access to opioid drugs, right? Then
We would have, for example, drugs
cannabinoids, which are derivatives of
from the cannabis sativa plant,
primarily THC, the
tetrahydrocannabinol,
but also others like HC, CBD and
all the synthetic versions that are
have been producing in these last
years, right? They're drugs, so what do they have?
an alteration of consciousness also
important at a perceptual level, at a
cognitive.
They can be addictive, even if they are not
too addictive when compared
with, for example, opioids, but
but they can become substances
addictive and can cause some problems
at the level of mental health in people with
predisposition to disorders such as, for example
For example, psychosis, schizophrenia,
bipolar disorder, etc., right? Even so
They have medical uses, huh?
fundamentally, then, for the management of
the side effects of
chemotherapy, for example, in cases of
cancer or in some pains or even in
in problems related to the
anxiety. Eh, luego tendríamos un perdón
that I cut you off, and there will be many myths, me
seeing if they are true or not. And I have
heard about addiction with the
cannabinoids. What is canid like?
Yes, cannabinoids are found in cannabis.
which is more mental. not so much
biological, right? It's like you have
addiction to smoking marijuana, but it's not
not that your body asks for it, but that you
Yes. Let's see, when we talk about addictions
divide them into physical dependence and the
Psychological dependence, isn't it? The
that your body adapts to a substance
And then in the absence of that substance, uh
is in a dysfunctional state or
Very difficult to manage, isn't it? By
For example, if you spend your time drinking
alcohol every day, if one day you stop
a rebound, that is, a situation in
which is going to have a lot of
issues. For example, it does exist in fact
death from lack of alcohol in
a person who has been drinking a lot
time. If you stop consuming in a
abruptly and not in a
progressive and de-escalation slowly, it can
a rebound occurs, which is called eh
eh Delirum Tremens, which is basically
a very strong imbalance of the
a body that can lead you to have, well
to die. In fact, there are people
who die, yes, from giving up alcohol
very long season drinking a lot
cantidades todos los días. That said, it's not
that you're going to die for a weekend
I've been drinking a lot this week and
Then stop drinking on Monday, that would be necessary.
further. But it is true that in
people who already have alcoholism
highly developed, which they carry a lot
time drinking large quantities
daily, they cannot suddenly abandon the
consumption because they can suffer from this
problema y pueden morir, ¿no? So,
That would be a physical dependency. EITHER
In other words, the body needs the substance, already
the substance. So, to abandon
a physical dependency you have to
normally make a reduction
gradual reduction of consumption to prevent it from
produce that imbalance that you
It might even reach you
kill. in the case, for example, of
alcohol, which is the one that most affects her
more lethal in this sense, or for example
Vencedinas are very high doses, do not
can abandon a Venetian blindfold suddenly
because it can produce a picture
Similar, isn't it? A little less, eh
situations that are also quite extreme.
Then we would have dependency
that reinforcement circuit of the
dopamine, also in that habituation that
the person may have to carry it out
of this substance. Or for example, many
Sometimes people end up...
developing one of these dependencies
psychological when they find that the
This consumption produces some kind of
advantage insofar as it allows them to
The best thing, for example, is to park a state
psychological, uh, that's being, uh, bad or
which is causing them suffering,
No? For example, a person who has
a trauma, a person who has a
to make sure it doesn't affect him in his
It is likely that the person will begin to
way, let's say, of coping or of or of
produce a subjective reduction of the
percepción del dolor psicológico. Is
In other words, the person may feel that those
things that worried him or that
They used to bother her, but she doesn't feel them as close anymore.
can lead to the person starting to
to abuse very constantly the
substance, right? It is true that both,
degree of psychological dependence. Is
That is, if you, for example, find
that consuming stimulants allows you
to function better in your day-to-day life, you
It allows you to be perhaps more focused
or it allows you to perform better, especially
in people who have problems with
attention, such as people with
ADHD, so it's logical that you end up
developing some degree of dependence
psychological effects of the substance. say,
"Hey, I'm studying, I'm not..."
concentrating, because I've missed it
maybe be able to take this substance
which helped me to be more focused,
"No?" Well, that kind of dependency is
a dependency that almost all
drugs can produce, to some extent,
No? But it is true that dependence
physiological or biological is a
dependence that not all substances
They produce, don't they? And in the case of cannabis
It is true that there is not a great deal of production
dependence, uh, at a physiological level, is
More of a psychological issue, isn't it?
For example, uh, one thing that happens to him
to many people with the topic of cannabis
It's just that he's getting used to it.
consume it regularly before
going to sleep, for example, or because of the
night, in the afternoon, or to finish at
to end the workday. So
There comes a point when they abandon
consumption will increase very abruptly
They're going to have trouble sleeping.
difficulty falling asleep,
to relax. But it is true that this
It's not a physical dependency, eh
necessarily. That is, the person
It probably doesn't have, let's say, a
rebound, let's say, at a physiological level by
You've stopped using cannabis, right?
Or for example, it's not going to be a
a rebound, let's say, very noticeable, but yes
It is true that it can have problems,
For example, to fall asleep,
for the best to carry out
certain activities that were
accustomed to carrying out under the
effects of the substance, right? This
Fortunately, well, if it's approached with
It addresses with a certain structure,
with a certain structure, with good
with, well, uh, with a mindset
of wanting to change that situation, no
Changing that situation is not usually very easy.
It is often very problematic because more
problematic because beyond a few
In a few days this usually happens
to rebalance and the person then begins
The person then begins to move away from
now to move away from that
better than that situation. But it is
situation. But it's true that there are times
It's true that sometimes...
that psychological dependencies
psychological dependencies can
can accompany a person throughout
to accompany a person throughout their life.
life. That is, the person who...
Fortunately,this is because,well,yes,itis
He's gotten better at socializing
under the influence of alcohol, it is
likely whenever found
a social situation think, "Joe, well
Maybe I should drink something.
"Alcohol, right?" I mean, that's that
Psychological dependence always always
It's going to be there, right? But anyway, uh the
a person can modulate it or
to get a little bit, to put a little bit of
which is not good for me because of this, because
that." And well, even though it's something that
Maybe the person will always have
certain certain memory of that of that
possibility, since it is not necessarily
It means that the person will be
always under the effects of the substance
or that I can't avoid it, right?
Simply put, well, that's it.
Psychological dependence develops over time
It gradually softens, the person gradually
accustomed to carrying out their
activities without the need for the
substance, but well, uh, it's something a
I remember that the person can
stay, right? In contrast, the physiological one,
Well, it's true that there comes a time when
the body already reaches, let's say, a
homeostasis, a balance in which already
is not needing the substance of
continuous form, right? Sometimes it's
It depends a lot on the situation
The person has context, because it is
uncontrolled or perhaps misuse
recreational without much control,
uh are normally modulated by
three families of variables that are the
which they call the Cimber Triangle,
No? Which are three legs, let's say, like
for example, the legs related to
the substance, which can be the dose, the
whatever type of substance it is, uh the
frequency of consumption, uh the
The purity you possess is adulterated, in
In short, all those kinds of variables. Then
the variables related to the
person, which can be your state, eh
baseline psychological state, if you have traumas, if
You don't have traumas, if you have one
biological tendency towards more addictions,
because some people may have one
certain greater vulnerability to the
addictions that other people have, right? to the
better people than in their family history
has had a lot of cases of
alcoholism, that kind of thing
characteristics that suit the person,
They usually, or perhaps they can facilitate
Those problems, right? Uh, for example, the
your age, whether you are male or female,
At a biological level it can also have
an impact on how they affect
substances to your brain, to your organs
vital. And then the third leg, which
It's also very important, it's the leg.
contextual. It's not the same, for example,
a person who consumes alcohol in a
social context that a person who
consumes alcohol, for example, in a
context of loneliness in his home. Uh, there
There are many very different risks in
as to what might happen. Or by
For example, it's not the same thing to take a
drink in a nightclub rather than having it in
a car at 120 on the highway. Wanna
to say that you can be the same
person, the drug is the same,
alcohol in the same dose, but changes
The risk you take if you're in
one context or another, right? Uh, also
What are the motivations of
consumption. It's not the same to consume for
to increase a situation of pleasure or of
social welfare or hedonism that
consume to escape a situation that
You are finding it stormy or difficult,
No? In other words, there are a lot of
variables that need to be taken into account,
No? And it's very important. And following a
little with the with the wheel, and
For example, the following family of
The substance would be drugs.
very frequently, although people don't
Coca-Cola, in Red Bull, in a bunch
of food or drinks we drink
regularly, it is undoubtedly a
psychoactive drug of the family of
stimulant drugs and it is a substance
that practically everyone or the
almost daily form to start their
tasks, their workday. That is to say,
that we also have a very strong inertia
large in drug use
stimulants, although it is true that
when we think of stimulant drugs,
It's most likely that it will come to us
mind illegal stimulant drugs,
No? For example, cocaine, like
authorized and used daily, by
For example, for the treatment of ADHD in
many children and many adults throughout the
world, right?
There are a lot of substances of this
family that normally have
used mainly for work,
for work, for activity
daily, to enhance the capacity
of concentration, energy, the
feeling good, motivation
even in wars, for example, the
methamphetamine use in the Second
World War. Uh, these are very, very cases.
well-known, aren't they?, of stimulants. Are
They usually overactivate the system
cardiovascular, raise the temperature
bodily and these two things can give
many problems in contexts because of
For example, recreational use, right?
Because very high doses can lead to
Important, right? Arrhythmias, heart attacks,
Body, right? Like heat stroke
that can occur in consumption. also
They can be addictive. It is true that the
Caffeine is not a highly addictive drug that
let's say. What's more, I imagine people
which is addicted to coffee, which is not
I can start the day without my coffee, right?
Of course, it's fundamentally an addiction
psychological in this case, for example,
because it's more like saying, "Hey, uh, I'm
I need it to shave my eyebrows, it
I need to work better or to
"Be more focused." Okay, that's a
That's a psychological addiction.
No? But if you, for example, stop
Drinking coffee, the addiction, let's say,
physics, which may be that maybe the
You may experience some pain in the first few days
headache or some physical discomfort, it is very
mild and usually lasts a very short time.
It's not a bit like addiction, because
For example, physics that can be produced at
Another very famous stimulant is...
nicotine. Nicotine is also a
stimulant drug, although it is true that
It's a milder stimulant; it doesn't have
such a stimulating power
noticeable as caffeine can have or
amphetamines or cocaine, but it's
a drug that has an effect
stimulant in the body and also
It produces quite a lot of dependence.
psychological, above all. I mean, you
It will last a few days, it's going to be a
need, as well as more consumption
related to the fact that the body...
He is not completely calm. what do you need
a little bit of the thing about tobacco that you
It makes you feel relaxed.
subjectively, even if it is a
stimulating, it can make you feel
relaxed because you already have one
The problem comes later with the
You already have a psychological addiction.
People are smoking and you are
thinking, "Damn, I'd like to smoke
"A cigarette, right?"
By association, right? Many times as
Are you making coffee? Because I need
my cigarette. That's all, that's all
eh marks of a dependency
psychological, associations, uh, when
You're with people and then you kind of...
The urge to do it arises, but it's not
Let's say your body needs to take that
Nicotine to feel good, simply
that your brain has become accustomed to the fact that
in certain situations, well, that
type of consumption is a consumption that you
It made you feel good, that you liked it,
that made you feel like you were
in the appropriate context. Well,
It has a lot to do with that, with the
relating to many people
sometimes or even with the form with the
that we have become accustomed to
Dealing with ourselves, right? In
In many cases, there are people who love it
So, I smoke when I get up
in the morning or when taking the
coffee. decir, pues son eh cosas que nos
We are used to it, but there really isn't one
physiological need that the body
I need nicotine, don't I? That's for sure.
That would happen with alcohol, that's for sure.
It would probably happen with drugs
opioids when taken for a long time
consuming them, but fortunately
Well, with tobacco, for example,
That habituation is very slight.
She has the body, doesn't she? There is a question
that you keep doing to me for a while
months and it is, what is this strange jug with
The one where you laugh at water in every episode?
Well, it's the Alcanatur jug, because
Yes, tap water is fine until
You find out it contains chlorine, metals
heavy metals, microplastics, and basically
the whole list of things you don't want
drink. And with plastic bottles,
If you're as paranoid as I am, more than
same. I don't want to drink the
microplastics and Al canatur filters them
all. But the best thing about this jug is that
Besides filtering all that, it alkalizes
The water adds natural antioxidants.
and it retains the good minerals. and
Moreover, it's the only pitcher that meets the requirements.
UNE149101 standard
which is made in Spain without BPAs or
strange plugs. Y además la jarra te
It comes with this reusable bottle
that you can use as many times as you
you want.
If both your family's health and the
Yours worries you, you can start drinking
cleaner water by clicking on the link
in the description and using the code
zoom out for a 10% discount. AND
Now back to the conversation. Well,
No, I'm sorry, I have to be honest.
with you. I'm sorry to Canatur, but
Yes, you do have something wrong with you, and I have to
say. When you've been at it for a while
By using it, you begin to notice the flavor
in plastic bottles, therefore
You won't be able to drink bottled water.
plastic because you'll want to filter it first.
Now, back to the conversation. And
With caffeine, then of course, you have
Drugs have to be seen as something negative.
For your health, right?
No, no, no, no, no he dicho eso. He
said that it has to produce a
psychological effect that is measurable, or
be, then, an alteration of the
consciousness, an alteration of the state
mental, emotional, psychological or of
behavior. But one important thing
which doesn't necessarily have to be added, that is,
associated with drugs, although it is true
which in many cases it is, is the
addictiveness or harm to health. The
drugs don't necessarily have to be
addictive or not necessarily have to
can cause harm to health, but it is true
that many of them at certain doses
in certain people and in
certain contexts produce that type
of effects, right?
Does caffeine have any harmful effects?
Or not? Man, caffeine is one of the
Few drugs, I'd say, but in doses, eh
Low levels are beneficial for health.
In other words, there are studies that link,
about four cups a day. From
detrimental, but up to four cups
It is considered that it can improve daily.
some cardiovascular health values
or even liver health, right? Is
In other words, that implies it is producing
a beneficial effect on the body.
Of course, it's true that it's difficult to
to dissociate what is the effect of the
caffeine, what is the effect of everything
Coffee, because coffee contains a
a lot of antioxidants and a
a lot of things that are positive for
the organism and we already know that, right?
So, it's not very clear if it is
exclusively caffeine or is that it
mixture of substances that is produced in
coffee, which many of them can
be quite positive for health,
No? But it is true that
unlike other drugs that
to cause damage, another thing is that it is
It is true that on a psychological level some
may have therapeutic uses
And there, the benefit can be...
To offset, let's say, the risk can
to compensate for the damage. In the case of coffee
Yes, we do have a physiological benefit.
Of course, in low doses, right? that's
And if he forgives,
but at high doses and it's a bit because
clearly detrimental and harmful. Is
I mean, a person who consumes doses
head, difficulty reconciling the
sleep, that is, insomnia, problems with
anxiety, problems even at the level
cardiovascular, how can it be, eh
tachycardia or elevated blood pressure and
in a very high dose of caffeine. Is
In other words, caffeine has a dose
lethal. In fact, there have been very many cases.
Few in the world, fortunately, but
There have been cases of people who have
died from an excess of caffeine or
por unasis de cafeína, ¿no? What happens
It is true that it is in the range of
about 100 coffees, which is very complicated
varios casos documentados. I loved you
preguntar sobre eso específicamente. HE
So, I mean, don't worry, as long as...
Put this paper down, I won't forget it
that [laughs] we have to finish the
I had COVID and my head is still spinning.
If I'm holding the sheet, there's no
problem. [laughs] Okay, it's like you who
return. E si te metieras, por ejemplo,
take it, I don't know. In theory, the way to
to take effect. Va a modular mucho el la
the behavior it will have at the level
a very high peak in blood and therefore a
very high peak effect or if we have a
effect as more moderate and then one more
prolonging time and more, one
gentler descent. But, uh, let's say in
In the case of caffeine, if we're talking about
are in the range of, let's say, below
about 100 mg, which is what is usually
containing a cup of coffee, either
There would be a huge difference, uh, if
por otra vía más rápida. It is true that
drinking it. it is more likely that you
produce, for example, a headache or
other kinds of problems, uh, if you're
sniffing what if you're drinking the eh
because of the speed at which it enters
blood, but let's say that at some
enormous in terms of toxicity that
can produce in the body a
dose snorted or drunk. It is true that
For safety, the most common form of consumption
always recommended for caffeine
The oral route; the nasal route will only...
Doing so only increases those risks or those
issues. Pero cuando hablamos de dosis
within the range of a normal dose either
is that there will be a difference
immense. In other words, the person is not going to
to die from taking the same dose of a
coffee through the nose. He's not going to die.
That's why he will die if he takes 10 times more.
doses, if you take a few doses, eh
markedly superior. So, I
Personally, I don't think it has much.
It makes sense, having a way to consume
which can be fatal if you use a route
which is much less safe and
which we also know can lead us
a. many more calculation errors in
Regarding the dosage, right? Because
When you drink a coffee, you know
perfectly the power it will have
ese café en ti, más o menos. But if you
You take a certain amount of caffeine and don't
You weigh it or you don't measure it, we don't.
We as a society are used to
to know that such a small mountain is the
equivalent to a coffee or not. In other words, there are
people who shop in a store, for
For example, as is happening today
in some cases. Uh, and in this
Okay, if you want, I can show you.
You see, I have to go to the backpack,
currently in some stores in
Powder format for snorting. that kind of
we can manage properly because we don't
we are used to handling the
caffeine through that route, right? So, that
problems that it can produce and I think
that using one having a way of
consumption
more like that. Pues eh como te decía, eh me he
brought here to show you one of the
caffeines that can currently be
They are being sold in some
tobacconists and such, which is basically the
Legal caffeine, the good old-fashioned kind.
but in powder form, in pure form, which
They add some flavoring, some kind of
of smell or taste so that it has some
It depends on the type of taste, and people sell it.
for sniffing. Básicamente el riesgo que
This is logically the difficulty
that we have to be able to measure
adequately dose when we are not
accustomed, logically. Uh, and well,
because they have different types of
flavors, smells, uh, they sell them
different brands. In fact, this is
something that has been done for a long time
time in countries like Austria or
Germany. In October, for example,
It's very common to snort caffeine mixed with it
with menthol, uh, it gives a flavor like
pleasant minty and gives a certain a
a certain feeling of energy that
alcohol. And many people use this.
when he has been drinking for a long time
beer and wants a little change
thirds. They snort this type of
powders that there actually has a
name, I don't remember right now, but
They are called cocaine in the prairie in German,
Cookens, I don't know what, and it's actually sold
there and this is a new thing that in
I had never seen Spain before, but it's
It's true that lately I've had them appear
summer or so it started, he started to come out
a lot, in fact there was a time when
of radio and media
What we were seeing was an increase.
in consumption in this form of
nose,
no not at all. Una ruta de consumo, a
uh or more or less hygienic and more or less
Dangerous, but let's say it doesn't exist
inyectarse cosas. That is true
more dangerous when used
type of consumption routes, okay? Hey,
firstly because of its pharmacological potency
increases. Es decir, el cuando tú una
When taken orally, the peak is higher
high, let's say, the peak in blood
it can cause that for a while
Y esto es peligroso, lógicamente. If a
cup of coffee instead, drink it for
100 mg and we snort them, it's going to
produce a peak that for some
minutes might be too many
for the body and it can be quite
disgusting. Some may occur
tachycardia, malaise, nervousness,
restlessness, insomnia, pain
head. But it's true that, well, uh
the routes of drug consumption are
something that has to do with the type of
treatment being done, if it
is it doing in medical use or what the
The user or the person who consumes it is
searching. Una persona que se toma un
coffee, because he's looking for a
stimulation that lasts for a while. Hey,
a person who is a strong blow from
the substance,
greater risks, with greater impacts on
health and then having another setback
strong that can make the person
That effect, right? And that, in fact, the
The most problematic consumption routes are
That's it, the intravenous, the smoking,
The sniffing, which is what a little bit eh
the most problematic drugs end up
being used primarily by that
type of roads, because they are the roads a
little that produces an effect like more
intense, but it also brings the
as a consequence of the fact that the Rap person has
a sharp drop that makes him need eh
to keep consuming, right?
using that route.
I don't get it. Let's keep the wheel turning.
Let's keep the wheel turning. Well,
We would have, for example, drugs in
pathogenic. Drugs in pathogens are
drugs that have a certain profile
Stimulating, but they're already starting to come in
in the more hallucinogenic effects, right?
category, of drugs in pathogenic
methamphetamine, which is the acronym for the
ecstasy, basically, that's sold in
nightclubs.
Ecstasy and MDMA are the same thing.
Yes. And no to glass.
Yes, in Spain, because in Spain we call
crystal to MDMA in crystal form,
But in the United States, crystal meth is
meth. Crystal meth.
Uh-huh.
Which is different. In other words, it's actually more
crystal really the crystal med because
They are like quartz crystals
transparent, very, very, very eye-catching. AND
Here in Spain, let's say MDMA, which
It's a kind of crystalline stone
translucent, which is being sold again
well, in, like, in little stones, in the middle
transparent, semi-transparent and that
People then hammer away and in the
What he does is wet his finger and put it in
in the mouth and such. That's true, although in
Let's call Spain crystal, actually
This leads to a lot of confusion, about
all now that
People have already, let's say,
accustomed to connecting the idea of
of the crystal with the crystal med of the
American series, right? In Spain the
again
It's usually MDMA again, and it's usually not
so crystal, not so crystalline, not so
American. Furthermore, the effect is very
different, which is also very
Important, isn't it? Then, [clears throat]
MDMA is the drug that is pathogenic because
excellence, is a substance that tends
These drugs are called empathogens.
They are also called tactogenic because
People use them a lot in therapy.
to connect with one
same. Se utiliza mucho, por ejemplo, en
management, trauma treatment, eh
to make it easier for the person to
reliving the trauma from a
emotion associated with trauma and such. And so
There are some interesting ones. in the
post-traumatic. But oh well, they are
substances that also have a lot
recreational. Por eso se han usado durante
produce a state such as
consumo en espacios de ocio. Oh well,
espacios de ocio. In fact, they are
substances that tend to greatly increase the
consumo de de éxtasis, ¿no? And this
It can also be administered at high doses, but
It can even be passed in doses
normal. There are people who may have
more propensity, let's say, to these
malignant hyperthermias, to these
increases in body temperature
who may even have problems with
Normal doses, right? In other words, here we have to
Be very careful with this type of
substances, because while it is true that
They generally don't give many.
problems in what for the much
that are consumed, it is true that from time to time
when quite a few cases occur
dramatic stories of people dying because
consumption, especially in leisure spaces
and especially related to having
mixed substances, with being in
[snort] very hot places, uh no
This kind of thing, right? Then
We would have psychedelic drugs, which
They are drugs that seem to me
superimposed by the potential
such enormous therapeutic potential that it has daily
It is being investigated. They're drugs, huh? Like
for example LSD, dimethyltryptamine,
silocybin, which is the principle
silocibecicensis fundamentally, eh,
neither physiological nor psychological. In fact,
are substances that when they turn from
a psychedelic drug trip, the
I'm eager to take another trip.
tired. Uh, it's like coming back from a trip
normal. The last thing you want is
Spending a few days at home, right? And this to him
It happens a lot to people when
vuelve este tipo de experiencias. Then
big. Es decir, no no se han dado
dose, right? Lo cual es pues complicado
No? Lo cual nos dice que son bastante
seguras a nivel fisiológico, ¿no? Which
tremendously
No? O sea, una persona puede tener un
Ready, right? Afortunadamente, cuando
I have controlled, in a context
eh acotado y bien controlado. Again
individual, right? Y de hecho, esto es lo
adicciones incluso. In other words, the
person. Y esto puede facilitar que la
consumo por otros medios, ¿no? In fact,
psychological disorders and everything points to
that we can see in the coming years
How do they start to be legalized, huh?
certain psychedelics in use
hospital, that is, in very high use
controlled, not so that the patient is
not to take him home, but so that he can be...
controlled in a hospital setting,
in a well-controlled clinical setting and
that this helps the patient in their process
Therapeutic, isn't it? In other words, psychotherapy
asistida con psicodélicos. We are not
talking about using the drug to cover it up
the disorder as it is done today
with antidepressants or
anxiolytics, but we are talking
of using the drug to enhance the
effect of verbal psychotherapy that the
The patient is carrying out with his
therapist, right?
And lastly we would have drugs, eh
dissociative. las drogasativas, eh, que
also along with drugs in
pathogens are currently getting into the
umbrella of psychedelic drugs
when we talk about research
clinic, because it's true that they have a
effects by similar mechanisms or with
Similar, well, drugs, huh?
dissociative, which are the ones that have
commonly used in, for example
In anesthesia, these are drugs that are very
dolor del cuerpo. Uh, they're used a lot.
ambulances. I am a volunteer for
SAMUR Civil Protection in Madrid, which
son las ambulancias básicamente. And uh
when we find a person, because
traffic, which is in a situation of
much pain, because it often uses,
se les administra queetamina. The
y y ¿por qué no morfina? It is also
fentanyl. Una persona con un dolor eh
often in a person who has
que hacer, ¿no? But it is true that the
patients, right? La queina tiene una
much larger. That is, if a
de lo que tu cuerpo necesita. And this
They are losing their lives due to overdoses
highly adulterated or either because they have
oxygen, right? esto que es la la muerte
opides. Afortunadamente para que suceda
substances. Then there are others too
these compounds and choose which one is the
More suitable for administration, right? But
these substances beyond use
recreational activity they may have, because of the
queina is used a lot in spaces of
Leisure, at raves, in different eh
formats for recreational consumption.
It's also important to remember that your this
famous person who is very popular right now, the
And what else does it have?
Ketamine. It again contains quinine
caffeine, but it can also be
amphetamine. Pero bueno, no hay una
receta, digamos, estándar. It's one thing
that has emerged from the street, let's say,
has arisen from the inventiveness of some
Therefore, there is no standardized formula
You're saying the IT has to be this, right?
Rather, it depends on what you want to do.
la persona que lo está fabricando. In
Spain, Energy Control, which is dedicated to
analyzing drugs and music festivals
in leisure spaces and also in their
caffeine-type stimulant or sorry or
amphetamine, but this does not mean
that it is the only thing it contains. Many
times it has been found and they have
found tusis that contain other
compounds, right? The only thing they have
common to all tusis at the moment is that
pink dye that they add, [laughs]
No? Pero luego lo que lo que lleve,
standardized. And this is a problem.
A person is consuming when they are
consuming a tusi. Uh, a lot of people don't
sabe lo que lo que esperar. Many people
70s, if I remember correctly, 70s and 80s
about psychedelic phenylethylamines,
the one with the tusi that we see in the street,
No? Aunque el nombre pueda ser
Similar, 2CB, TCIB, Tusi, that's there
El TCB este es psicodélico o qué es. Yeah,
feniletilamina psicodélica. What do you want?
Say this? Que tiene una estructura, un
phenylethylamine skeleton, that is,
similar to what they might have
stimulants of the family of the
Amphetamine, methamphetamine, but uh
It has an effect that is psychedelic and
tendría el LSD. In other words, it's a
It enters the realm of drugs.
No? Produce [resoplido] eh eh eh
very important changes in perception
like a drug, like very, very special,
efecto psicodélico, ¿o no? or was it a
There, right? Nuevamente las drogas
molecule,
MDMA is a molecule, three quat
methyl ethylamine, uh, methamphetamine is
molecule, which is trimethylhantine, or
sea, siempre hablamos de moléculas. In
Molecules, right?
peligrosas se vuelvan. I actually
gives us not only gives us power, but
drugs. Pues en este caso cuando
knowledge because it is a mixture whose
proportions are totally
unknown, it depends on who has
made the mixture, whose ingredients are
also unknown, and those are a
a lot of ingredients to increase
el riesgo de una droga. When a
person handles a drug they know, uh,
which also has not only knowledge
not a theorist of what drugs are, but
that the analyst also knows exactly
the purity percentage and the molecules
that it contains and so on, all that is uh
things that will make it much safer
the handling of that substance. Without going any further
Far beyond that, we can go to medical use, the
fentanyl, which is such a substance
lethal and so dangerous today that
100,000 people have been killed in
The United States alone in a year
overdose, it is a substance that is
It is used daily in all hospitals
of the world and that barely produces deaths
in that context. Because?
because it's handled by doctors who know.
handling fentanyl. It is a substance
pure that has a pharmaceutical origin,
purity, dosage, and everything.
So, with those premises of
quite safe. Now, if we
We go to the street where we don't know the
purity of what they're giving you, huh? No
we know the adulterants that may be present
carrying that substance, which can be
far more dangerous than the
Those are elements that make a big difference.
the more dangerous the psychoactive substance,
No? That's why I always talk about...
finally the drugs when they are in a
regulated market, in which there is a
regulation, I'm not saying it's legal
and that it is accessible to everyone nor
Much less, I say there is one
regulation that controls purity, that
control who has access to that substance,
What does the person who accesses that know?
substance, tests, uh, how to have
driving, uh, controls that establish
a knowledge base for those
people who will be handling the substance,
whether they are medical professionals, or uh
people who are going to use it for
a purpose that is not strictly
medical. All of those are safeguards that
greatly increase the safety of
substance. There will never be one
seguridad total. Drugs always
They have risks. There is no way to delete
those risks except not consuming them.
Obviously, if you never use cocaine
You're going to die from cocaine use.
But it is true that those risks
They can be reduced.
Hm. In other words, it's not the same to take eh
fentanyl on the street without knowing
the actual purity of fentanyl that
You have in your hands, the dose that you are
taking, uh, without being very clear if it
You are taking it with a purpose
recreational or because you're fleeing from a
trauma that is tormenting you, that
take it in a well-controlled context
by a medical professional who is
administering for a specific pain that
you are having in a dosage
perfectly measured, in a purity
perfectly known, without adulterant,
without such, with an injection material or
clean and hygienic venipuncture site. All
Those are measures that unfortunately the
The criminalization of drugs has led to
that they don't occur so much on the ground and
give much more
Problematic consumption, right? Is
In other words, all those things in markets
regulated, purity, for example, the
We don't have to drink alcohol these days.
worry that alcohol can lead
methyl alcohol and blind us. That
It's something that happened during the law
dry in the United States when alcohol
It was prohibited, but today,
Fortunately, it doesn't happen because there is a
market that regulates the purity of
alcohol, which regulates the labeling of
What you're buying is what it is, right?
This doesn't exist in illegal markets.
In other words, illegal markets can...
Fortunately, in most of the
cases, when we talk about drugs of use
recreational drugs like MDMA, like the
amphetamine, uh, drugs like cannabis, no
It's so common that they're giving you
super-lethal, super-dangerous things,
No? They usually give you what
you are acquiring, more or less pure,
But that's usually how it is, but it's true
that you never have the guarantee and that it can
pass. And also, if you move beyond its use
recreational and you get into drugs for recreational use
more problematic like opioids, there
large and the purity is usually very low and
purity fluctuations are
extremely dangerous. what you were taking
week, you take it the following week, the
same amount and it turns out they've given it to you
given with double the purity and you are
taking double the dose without knowing it
You, right? In other words, there are a lot of
of problems, eh, that come, that are
They stem from the illegality of drugs
that do not exist in the markets
regulated, problems that disappear in
the moment drugs are regulated
because they make some of these
substances are much more dangerous than
what they could be in a context of
a good example of that. The Tusi is a
a substance about which we know nothing.
Fortunately, it's not producing a large number of cases.
number of deaths, not even close. No
is a substance that is being
excessively lethal because as you
It mentions ketamine above.
It has a large safety margin. Is
That is, the active dose to the lethal dose
There is a big difference. But if for
For example, if we were talking about the
consumption of street mixes
related to opioids, such as
the case of fentanyl in the United States,
Let's not forget that fentanyl is a
adulterant, that is, the people who
Acquire fentanyl, normally not
heroin. The thing is, they give it to him in
adulterated heroin reality with
fentanyl or they give him diluted fentanyl and
That's much more dangerous because there isn't
Yes, fluctuations in purity and
The power is enormous. Well, that kind of
of casuistries occur in that type of
markets, but these are problems that
Let's talk, these could be non-type problems
to know what will happen to you with the effect
of the substance like your problems
that can kill you, like the
in the case of opioid drugs that
dangerous and much more lethal. No
I'm curious, Anton. Now then
We've finished the wheel [laughs]
dissociative.
I think it's a curious name, don't you? I mean,
that someone who has never taken
nothing dissociative. How can you
Explain what that means? Well, one
It feels difficult to explain. In fact,
the effects of drugs often
They are very difficult to describe with
Words, right? But I would say that the
The dissociative effect is a kind of
a feeling like you're separating
of your body, right? A feeling as if
You move a little away from your body. Of
In fact, when a person takes a dose
very high levels of queetamine, eh, suffers from a
One effect is called a hole.
K, which is called the K-hole because the
People feel like they are often
as if it were underground
or or half half buried, right? very rare
motor coordination. In fact, when
move, you are motionless and
practically in another state, in another
No? In fact, it is an effect, the one that
Amamina has a tremendous effect, eh
Psychedelic, isn't it? That's why he goes inside
And one thing I forgot
I should mention beforehand, and it's very important
is that the one that is also currently the
only drug that is authorized for use
doctor with psychedelic effect. That is to say,
It is the only drug that, to this day,
For example, a person with depression
In Spain you can go to a public hospital
and the psychiatrist can prescribe a
ketamine trip.
Ah. And it's being done. What happens is
that ketamine is not used, it is used
esketamine, which is an enantiomer, a
of the molecules have many times a
forms a right-handed left-handed or SR, it is
That is to say, it has two orientations,
in the case of ketamine, since they have patented it
one of the orientations of the molecule,
which is the S form of the
molecule of the S antimer of the
ketamine, and that's what they use in...
Therapy, right? It's called esketamine, it's
Very expensive, but oh well, it's covered by
the one for social security, that is to say
It's costly and it really is a therapy
which is already being done in
Many European countries, in states
United, and in Spain specifically, because
It is perfectly available. Yes indeed,
It's not a top-notch therapy.
line, that is, a person with
depression, the first thing it asks for, no.
It could be the queina. That's for
people who have had several
failed therapeutic attempts, have
tested with antidepressants, with therapy,
they haven't managed to solve it and
then therapy can be offered to them
uh, conquetamine, right? What's up?
varias formas de abordarla. Ideal
It would involve doing assisted psychotherapy with
ketamine, that is, there is a base
psychotherapeutic and then the
ketamine is used to facilitate or
accelerate the therapeutic process. But it is
It is true that nowadays in the
hospitals, given the lack of staff
and the available hours of psychologists and
Furthermore, what is being done
basically it's administering the quein
directly as a drug and, uh, many
Sometimes that already produces an improvement in
The patient sometimes doesn't, but oh well.
that we can say that it can already be done
therapies eh of the family of the
psychedelic therapies, legally in
in hospitals, hand in hand with the
ketamine therapy. Let's hope that the
in the coming years more will join this therapy
Well, silocybin, when combined with DMT,
other molecules that may have a
an effect even more interesting than that of
la propia quetamina, ¿no? But come on, the
dissociative effect, as its name suggests
separation. And that's basically it
drugs, for example, like gas
It has also been used for many years
It has been used, for example, for the
Dentists have used it a lot. In
The United States is still used, eh
I use a lot of nitric oxide for that. Are
all drugs that produce this effect,
No? Dissociation, the feeling of
separation, right? Uh, it's true that
Well, it's a complicated effect of
describe. Para algunas personas es muy
unpleasant, for other people it is very
pleasant, that is, that also depends on
how how how how you experience it in a
subjective level, but it is true
which from the outside is an effect that produces
a lot of motor incoordination, a lot
difficulty moving, people
It's difficult to move, and in very high doses it's...
that remains motionless, that is, is
practically frozen and the feeling
as if unable to move, as if...
like good, like trapped, a feeling
very rare, very rare. Anton, tengo, bueno,
It was to talk a little about psychedelics,
Of course, they've been popping up and I love the
drugs, because we don't get involved a little
in psychedelics.
Psychedelic, isn't it? He
Psychedelic Renaissance in Your Book
What does that imply? What does it mean? Yeah.
Well, I have two books, one is the
Psychedelic Renaissance that I address
I'm addressing that beginning, right? And then the
world as simpler, which is the
It is being discovered in science
producing a true revolution in
the treatments. psychological,
primarily of disorders such as
I want to know everything, from how
desde todos los ámbitos, porfa. Okay,
Well, let's see, uh, to start with something
I started in this field, in the
field of psychoactive drugs in
psychoactive substances, which I later became.
European Drug Agency and so on, but
This field, uh, was the one where I spent a
depression, eh, pretty bad about
at 22 years of age upon completion of
career. I was very empty, I felt very
lost, uh, I had nothing, let's say,
sense. Empecé a perder un poco el
interest in things, it was, then
years of doing conventional psychotherapy,
anxiolytics, without a significant effect,
Let's say, without a significant positive effect,
years. Concretamente, a partir de los
research. una muy importante hubo
millennium and uh, although it is true that it is already
I had investigated in the past, because
fairly important psychedelic in the
The 1950s and 60s, uh, for political reasons and
for other types of cases, not only
political, but also scientific and
public health, it remained, let's say, uh, it remained
that process came to nothing or was aborted
research and now it has
It's back with a lot of force, hasn't it? Herein
In this context, well, I decided...
try assisted psychotherapy with
psychedelics. It went great for me, I mean,
I had two psychedelic experiences
in a controlled environment with a
formed, uh, with a preparation, with a
monitoring during the experience and
then with a well-integrated process
estructurado y demás. He took me out
directamente de la depresión. I don't
I had it again, I was never sad again
Never again. All that loss is over,
all that emptiness, all that e
What did you feel? Because?
Well, the truth is that it's very difficult to
write. O sea, de hecho, las
Psychedelic experiences are considered
which are in many cases ineffable, or
In other words, they can't easily be put with
It was truly a feeling of
immense reconnection with everything that I
surrounded, with the people, with my
family, with my friends. Uh, let's say that
my priorities or the things that I
worried about life changed
totally, that is, things to the
importance, which were worrying me
Many things took a back seat. the
things changed that had been
in short, that they were good things
[clears throat] important things that I had in
life, but let's just say there was
lost,
I wasn't taking them into account that much,
for they regained prominence, they returned
to be important things, well, that's it, the
the connections with people, the the
of things that didn't matter to me that much, of
They soon returned to occupy the part
central to my existence and that
It was incredibly therapeutic for me,
tremendously, isn't it? then all the
psychotherapeutic therapeutic work that
It's done with all that experience, because
It's not just the psychedelic experience
brain, which we'll talk about now, but
but what is then done in therapy with
That's it, right? The important thing is that or
That is, a very important thing that the
What people need to understand is that
psychedelic-assisted psychotherapy
It is assisted psychotherapy with
psychedelics. In other words, we are not
so that they forget about the
No? That's what's being done now with the
No? En plan de drogarte para que no
Think a lot about everything that worries you
Or so you can relax, right? With
los psicódricos es al revés. With the
and really get to the bottom of the matter
of what you're really eh
causing that disorder, right? HE
It tries to go to the bottom, it tries to make the
psychedelic is a tool like a
scalpel. que permite al cirujano acceder
Fix it, right? Pasamos de un modelo en
dolor, o sea, un malestar. That is to say,
We use things that, well, as it deals with
back pain with a
opioid or with ibuprofen, which yes
cirugía, a operar. So, let's go
try to fix what's happening
there so I can sew it for you and that's it
durante todo el tiempo, ¿no? And that's a
las drogas psicodélicas. It's a change
paradigma muy grande en salud mental. EITHER
Strength, isn't it? Pues es un cambio
Many times, right? que pues muchas veces
Suddenly, they find themselves in front of
their own tumor, and they have a kind
as an interaction with him and they change
completely his perspective of his life
or they realize that they have to
value the short lifespan they have
They remain and take full advantage of it and move on to
I really want to see it as an opportunity
to live a few days that maybe another
people haven't had the opportunity to
live. In other words, it's a change of mindset.
very important, a change of
Perspective, isn't it? In fact, there are many
experience that many had
astronauts when they were launched into
the land and suddenly its problems
He's testing something, I don't know what, suddenly
That disappeared because suddenly they happened
realize that we are a tiny thing in the
immensity of space and of the
existence, right? Es decir, esa bueno, es
a real change of perspective.
A metaphor. Claro, eso literalmente
The further you go, the less eh
Yes, and that's been studied, it's called
the perspectives effect. He studied the
astronauts who were launched into the
first spacewalks, the first
space travel during the career
space in the United States and is a
effect that is studied at the level
Psychological, isn't it? And it's a change of
total perspective. I mean, suddenly the
things that worry you on a daily basis, in
which you are totally embedded
constantly, they come to be seen as a
which they don't really have any of
importance compared to the rest of the
which is existence, with being well
surrounds, with relationships, with the
well-being, that is, all that kind of stuff
that in our daily lives we have very
often isolated because we are
focused on the problems of the day
elsewhere. No
Psychedelics?
Psychedelics. Well, there are many ways
to actually do it. Eh, el ser humano
a lot of techniques that allow the
altered or expanded, depending on how
be very useful in this type of
contexts, right? For example, the
own other-tropic respiration or even the
método winhof en algunos casos. I mean,
There are techniques [snort] that allow you
to arrive, but it is true that the
This, I think, is quite complicated
unless obtained with other techniques,
consistente durante mucho tiempo. Is
very seriously it probably
alcanzar estos estados a placer, ¿no? Is
awareness. Pero es cierto que cuando
un meditador de 30 o 40 años. In fact,
What's more complicated is that a person
como puede ser la meditación, ¿no? And so
complejo de de instaurar, ¿no? Those are
tiempos de guerra, pero no viceversa. is
guerra ese tipo de de hábitos, ¿no? In
to be able to reach these states if you
They are therapeutic, and if you want to do it...
what most people who
develops a habit or has
beneficial experiences with drugs
psychedelics in well-lit spaces
professionals and others. Then, many of
They develop this type of
breathing exercises
reach states, although not so
This, right? Pero digamos que la
tool for the person who arrives
Like this one, the ideal one, in my opinion, would be
el uso de drogas psicodélicas. Always,
Of course, we're talking about
controlled contexts. eh va con una
control muy muy concienzudo, ¿no? No
We're talking about people when
Home, right?
No? Así como el fentanilo puede ser muy
psychedelic drugs. They're not going to be
No? Y y ¿qué te hacen los psicodélicos
in the brain? That's a very good question.
figure out. O sea, es una ciencia muy
la madurez psicodélica. But hey, uh
We will arrive. el el tema de del efecto de
of an effect at a morphological level, that is,
brain derivotrophy factor or factor
neuronas empiecen a crecer, ¿no? EITHER
No? De hecho, se ha visto en estudios,
you administer psychedelic drugs, such as
una pérdida de sinapsis. the person,
vueltas constantemente, ¿no? The
are of interest to the person. Or for example,
In the case of addiction, that can be done
The cycle can only become impoverished in
the substance or what results or in what
which is the person's addiction, which
It may not be substance, but it may be
Whatever, right? So this is a
The effect of psychedelics, right? HE
can see how a one is produced
generation of new synapses. In fact,
It has been observed that in mice, by
For example, the models that are used
to study depression they produce that
loss of synapses, that loss of
connection between neurons that with one that
with even punctual management
the effects of a psychedelic drug are reversed, or
That mouse increases its
number of neuronal connections
after a psychedelic experience and
recovers part of what it has lost because
That depression, right? And then, in addition,
This is also linked to the ability to
the neurons to reconnect, that is,
what is called neuroplasticity, the
that capacity that those neurons have not
just connecting with new ones
neurons, but also to change those
neural networks. And that's very useful.
because a person who has to change
their habits, that they have to change their
way of seeing the world in therapy can
He will achieve it, but he will achieve it.
a base of much exposure to therapy, or
that is, a long therapeutic process. But
Psychedelics shorten
that therapeutic process and condense it
because they make the effect or the
the effectiveness of that psychotherapy is greater.
Let's say the brain that is
receiving that psychotherapy is more
soft, it is more susceptible to change,
It's easier for him. I mean, it's like a
metal, a metal that is solid, that is
very difficult to change, but suddenly
We heat it up, it becomes more malleable.
Well, this is somewhat what happens in...
a brain when a person takes a
psychedelic drug in the days
Later ones have more neuroplasticity and
greater ease in producing changes or
then they're already recorded in the brain, right? AND
This, I insist, can be very useful for
the good, but also the bad. Is
In other words, if a person has trauma
psychological during an experience
psychedelic and is not adequately addressed
in therapy with an appropriate process of
integration in the following days, that
trauma, let's say, can crystallize,
in quotation marks, and make it more
complicated after boarding in the
future. the person can keep the
trauma, digamos, grabado. That's why
It's important that psychedelics are made
always in highly controlled contexts,
adequate screening to ensure that
The person does not have psychotic disorders
latent that can be made visible nor
so that it will bloom during the
psychedelic experience and so what if that
It always happens in a context in
which can be handled well
situation and then a
suitable integration process for
guarantee [snort] that we say that
one in a useful experience for the
person and does not remain crystallized as
como un trauma, ¿no? That's what it all is
work is being done on the processes of
integrations that come after the
A psychedelic experience, isn't it?
where psychotherapy is done, where
He does the entire psychotherapeutic approach,
No? This, this process that we have
explained, which in fact in some
animals has managed to demonstrate that
is even correlated or may
even produce an increase
even of new neurons, especially
in new areas in some brain regions
specific ones such as the vulva
muy relacionado con la memoria. This,
important. Se producen muy pocas muy
grown-up, right? In brains, let's say more
It gives more to the birth of new neurons,
con la vejez, ¿no? Well, it seems that
It appears that there is an increase in the
brain, right? But also at the level of
electrical communication of neurons,
There are also very important changes. By
For example, there is a network in the brain that
It is the default neural network, which is a
network that has a lot of functions.
Uh, actually, well, it's called redal because
default because it is usually active when
We are, let's say, in a state like
contemplative of thinking about
our things and so on. And it's a network
which, for example, in people who have
depression, and post-traumatic stress,
addictions, she is overactive
generally. And what does this tell us?
That person is not here and now, they are
He's ruminating a lot, isn't he?
In fact, uh, anyone who has
gone through a process of addiction, by
a process of having trauma or even
tell us that it really is a process in
who is thinking a lot, has a lot
constantly thinking, right? And so
your head, especially if you're giving it
dwelling on negative thoughts,
Harmful thoughts, it's very complicated
that the person will be okay. And the
psychedelics, what they do in this
The case is, uh, what has been seen in
neuroimaging studies, especially with
magnetic resonance imaging scanners
functional, with different tests, eh that
allow us to see ourselves as neurons
They are communicating with each other, it's
Psychedelics shut down the network, huh?
They either disrupt or destabilize the default neural pathway,
No? What they do is that the brain, uh
instead of being so focused on himself
himself, in the ego, let's say, which is of
made one of the structures uh the
let's say neuronal structures in the
that the ego is based on, is
basically the default neural network,
What they're doing is destabilizing all of this.
and for a while they make the ego...
dissolve and the person instead of being
to think, to mull things over,
I went as if I were becoming part of it.
All of its context, the whole thing, right? a
as a mystical experience and in fact it is
It is scientifically validated. That is to say,
We have questionnaires such as the MQ, MEQ,
which is a questionnaire that is Mystical
Experience Questioner, which allows us
assess the level of intensity that has
had the mystical experience in the
of the ego, let's say, there has come to be in
That experience, right? And that's a
a process that, while it sounds very...wú,
very much like very spiritual and such, in
reality when we talk about when it
We approach it from the most
It makes perfect scientific sense. Has
A lot of sense, huh, at a level...
neuronal, at the level of
neuroscientist of how it works
brain, right? If that person who is
obsessive, related to his trauma, with
his depression, combined with his addiction,
We are able to stop that flow and do
that the person is in the place, let's say,
more present in the here and now,
which is something that can achieve the
psychedelics, the person will be
much better, and then the therapy works
far better. And this is what you see
Then in the studios, right?
The higher the level of eh
mystical experience, in quotes, huh
which can, I insist, be approached from a
some parts are more religious, more mystical,
but it can simply be understood as
subjective and one and move on, let's say, to
to unify temporarily, that is, at the level of
phenomenological experience. I'm
hablando lógicamente, ¿no? That this
happens in real life, [laughs] right? But
Yes, that's how the person experiences it.
live that unites, that is, that I know that
let's say the barrier between the self and the
Furthermore, between my thoughts and the rest
dissolves and the person, let's say, who
becomes part of the whole during
a while or their feeling or what they experience
person. That's tremendous
therapeutic. Extremely therapeutic.
Uh, and at the level of neuroscience, that is, at
rather at the level of neuroimaging, one can
See how this has to do with it or is related.
correlated with that
disruption of the neural network by
defect, which is that the
brain instead of communicating eh passing
always through a filter, let's say, through a
very specific hub, that disappears and
then enormous chaos ensues
brain that is correlated with
This experience is mystical, isn't it? with
this experience of reconnecting with the
an environment that then turns out to be quite
therapeutic when when we see the
results this has on depression
And in psychopathological states, right?
I don't understand it, Anton, how can
Could it be a substance? Where does that come from?
substance and why does it create that? Know?
[laughs]
this. This is much more complicated than that.
to know why deep down, well, to
co-evolution that we have had
mammals with plants, the most
It's called a secondary metabolite, because
It is not necessary for the plant to...
way of life, that is, let's say, for their
substance. If it produces this substance, it is
because she's using it for something
in the context that they can of some kind
They can help or harm you.
What is the plant or what? In other words, the
For example, if we talk about
psychedelics, psychedelics are
está presente en la en el veneno. Well,
The Bufo alvarius toad produces it, right? is
with drug interactions and
farmacológicas, ¿no? In Spain we have
tenemos un caso de hace unos años. Hey,
psychedelics. Los cactus, sin ir más
Saint Peter.
also. Here I come, here I come. Then there are
fungi. Los hongos, por ejemplo, e
from other families. And then, for example,
diríamos que es semisintética. Because?
hace a nivel de laboratorio, ¿no? By
que yo sepa, no se ha encontrado. I don't know
given. Esto, por ejemplo, ha pasado con
Hey? Pero luego me luego me me vendrán a
la mente y te lo digo, ¿no? But come on
que esto pasa con muchas sustancias. Of
en en el cerebro humano. They are substances
presentes en el cere humano. We don't know
metabolism. I mean, to, I don't know, to
to process tryptamines, such as
serotonin, for example, or the
melatonin, uh, can be produced uh
Let's say when these molecules are broken, it becomes
small incidents can occur accidentally
quantities of DMT or 5 of MT, but in
reality may also fulfill a
We've discovered this, haven't we? Maybe they are
related to neuroplasticity, to
The best thing is the shape of our
brain to activate neuroplasticity
so that we can adapt to things more
quick in stressful or stressful situations
gran necesidad, ¿no? And that's why it's possible
See those increases at best DMTO
5 METs in these types of situations, no
It is not clear what the function is.
biological if they have it, but yes
that we know to be, that is to say, have
appeared in trace dose analyses,
That is, very small doses, but yes
We have small things in the human brain
quantities of DMT and 5 medmt, although
if we are not clear about what the function is, if
They do have some, right? And the to the
question of what the function of
These substances produced in the
plants, most likely they are
have to do with the plant being
trying to modify the behavior
From the predator that eats it, right?
So, what's going on? that could be
so much looking for eh to be toxic
for that predator, eh something that no
In my opinion, they would do very well because the
Of course, silocybin is not...
toxic, at least, for the
[snort] mammals.
In other words, if they are trying to
They're not doing a very good job of killing you,
[laughs]
They're not doing very well, but
There is another possibility that in my
That opinion is more plausible, and that is that
that modification of the behavior of
predator is not intent on killing it,
but rather be directed, for example, to
that disperses spores, for example. Is
In other words, I make the person who
It's consuming me, making me disoriented and...
to become disoriented, perhaps scattered
It makes me, well, I'm like a mushroom.
pueda crecer en otros lugares, ¿no? By
For example, that is, for instance, the
Caffeine is undoubtedly a drug that
It's not psychedelic, logically, but
Well, it's a drug that plants...
Nothing, but they use it so that, uh, the
insects, for example, that eat that
plants die. Because of the caffeine, then
It is lethal to many insects. That
happens? That we mammals do not
It doesn't kill the doses, but it puts us, it puts us
It activates and gives us energy. So,
We've given it a use that...
That's the original use it had.
molecule, we have given a use that
It works in our favor, doesn't it? That's going to
our such. Well, in the case of the
Psychedelics may be that
insects that eat fungi. But
that also in mammals has the
functionality of making the mammal
become disoriented and then scatter them
spores of that fungus in other places or
that maybe the mammal won't then
so strange, and then never eat again
further. In other words, it's not very clear which one
That's the function, but what is there is
Of course, if the plants generate
These substances are because plants and
fungi are because they want to induce a
change in behavior in their eh
Whether it's insects, or whatever it is, right?
Because the plant wouldn't have any.
need to produce this substance. AND
if this is happening and if the plants it generates are doing well.
substance, the fungi that generate this
evolutionarily and to prevail over the others,
That is, to reach our present day, no
to become extinct along the way, is because this
It's something that has been useful to them when
of being selected in the process
Evolutionary, isn't it? In other words, maybe
Mushrooms do exist today.
The cbecubensis thing is because humans
after living through such experiences
curious about them, we have said, "This
We have to take care of it and there are
and we must ensure that it continues to exist,
No? In other words, I don't think that's it.
not the only reason by any means, but oh well.
When a human being finds that a
The plant is useful for its purposes, it is
more likely that plant will survive,
because we generate a selection
artificial, but it is a selection that is
often equivalent to evolution,
No? So, well, just like that
We have chosen the best apples
They know that they are meatier and more
large, and less toxic tomatoes,
toxic, just like all nightshades
They are toxic to animals, but
we have been selecting the most...
the one with the most flavor, the one with the least
It was toxic, and even today, well...
Look, the plants that we
We cultivate a selection of these that
most have been useful to us. Well, the same thing.
This can happen with psychedelics. To the
Over the years we've gone too, eh
appreciating that there are plants that are
capable of altering our consciousness
so that it may be useful to us,
No? And in the end, well, look, in the end we
Just like coffee, coffee, for example,
It is a shrub that is now cultivated
extensively throughout the world because it is
valuable to us, but maybe
Coffee in nature today does not
there would be no more chances of
to survive, which is one type of other
plant, right? But what about us?
It is valuable to us, so we cultivate it more.
Well, there are many theories about it,
But what does seem clear is that
It's logical to assume that these
The molecules had a clear function of
in view of other organizations that do not
They were the plant itself. In other words, no
[clearing your throat] serves a function for the
facing external bodies that may
be insects, animals, or other types of
floors. And there we probably have
found this utility that we don't know
if it's the original one the plant had in
It's having that use, isn't it? Now
same
conspiracies, Anton, about the
ban on psychedelics
I forbade
There are many, that's true. [laughs]
I want to delve a little into that area
Less scientific, huh, to ask you about your
opinion and such without taking a stand or whatever you
you want to, but it is true that
It seems strange, doesn't it? como una droga o
psychoactive substance, such as
You want to call, who's helping you, right?
connect neurons and that stretches you
identidad, como yo lo veo, ¿no? When
When you meditate, it's like you stop
Believe in who you are and start to see
to other places simply because
You're kind of working your brain out
some way,
Yeah? No, no, the capacity they have to
to deconstruct social structures,
That is, when people have
psychedelic experiences such as
He says, "Well, why is this person going
to command me?", No, and they occur
things that are then closely associated with
with rebellion or with or with movements
social and that in fact, well, uh
were one of the elements, I believe,
most important in supervision.
Indeed. I mean, uh, me neither
I'm so naive as to say, I mean,
In other words, I'm neither naive nor am I
conspirator. I mean, let's say that
I have a slightly more...
centered. Well, I'm not naive to say that
Psychedelics were banned
exclusively because they were very
The government did it out of pure love for the
salud de los de los ciudadanos. But
I'm not that much of a conspiracy theorist either.
to believe that psychedelics were banned
exclusively because the government wanted
They were afraid that these substances
could replace their drugs
And this with just a few administrations
pharmaceuticals and you become a person
of a natural substance. No, I don't believe in
None of these extremes, no
Let's say, but I do believe that everyone
factors played a role
On the one hand, without a doubt, the
psychedelics when they were banned
late 1960s were
producing some health problems
public. Maybe they weren't problems after all.
so big as to justify their
prohibition. In fact, to this day the
Alcohol causes health problems
huge public figures and tobacco, and they are not
prohibited and we've had them, or
That is, alcohol kills 3.3 million
people in the world per year. That is
responsible for a lot of accidents
traffic, fights, violence. and not
That's why it's prohibited, so to speak. Uh, in
In contrast, psychedelics, well, yes
They caused accidents; there were people who...
He consumed them in inappropriate contexts,
people who had very experiences
traumatic effects from the use of psychedelics,
people who even had psychotic episodes
for consuming psychedelics. But that
Let's say it's a reason, but it's not a
prohibition, because to this day,
I insist, we have the alcohol and we have the
tobacco that kills millions of people in
tobacco causes 6.6 million deaths worldwide each year.
of people in the world per year. And not because
Those are prohibited. Well, that's what I think.
which was also mixed in, of course,
with the theme of the counterculture, or
that is, from the emergence of a rebellion
Very large youth against the status
quo that threatened to destabilize
American politics, especially because
the topic of the Vietnam War, with
different processes that at that time
because there was a major confrontation against
they or she, for example, the movements
for civil rights, for equality
racial, pacifism, all that was
movements that were very anti-establishment. in
That was a very anti-establishment moment, wasn't it? And not
I say that psychedelics produced
Those movements, but without a doubt
Yes, they did feed them. In other words, the
psychedelics, the psychedelic experience
is closely related to that type of
peaceful, much more unitary, less
related to inequalities, with
social structures and so on.
Also, of course, an element of,
Well, of industrial interest. In other words, the
Psychedelics were substances that...
They had a more complex handling than what
may have an anxiolytic. A
You give the anxiolytic to the person and
The person calms down, that's it. You don't have
that being in a prepared place, no
You need to have a therapist for 4 hours
accompanying the person in a
Amazing experience, simply the
You give it and that's it. The person can
Take it home, you can take it every day.
days and that will lower his anxiety
Of course, this is not without its problems.
additions, problems of
long-term neurotoxicity that
Lasciadzepinas clearly have and that to
Today they are increasingly focused on the
table and are causing many problems,
especially in terms of diseases
neurogenerative, when people are very
He is older and takes anti-anxiety medication every day.
to sleep, which is something that
Unfortunately, in Spain it is very
frequent, very frequent in older people.
But anyway, psychedelics, let's say
which were slightly more tools
difficult to handle, much more
powerful, of course, than the
anteolytics or antidepressants, but
with a potential, in my opinion, greater
to actually solve the problem and not
so as not to simply cover it up,
No? What's happening? that have less
business, it is also much less profitable
at an industrial level eh give to a person
an intensive therapy, let's say, once
that in a few days you can
sell her a pill so that she can
Take it every day for a long time
time, because that generates much more
business. Además, puedes patentar la
molecule of the pill so that you
return money only to you. Uh, and the
Most psychedelic drugs are
patentability is very narrow. Is
In other words, they are substances that, well,
Yes, maybe you can patent the
specific capsule in which it will go
managed and so on, but let's say
that it won't all be yours. I mean,
another company can produce the same
molecule with a different capsule and
That is, there is less room for
patentability, right? More is less
Business, isn't it? So, well, I think
that although it is not solely a topic
that the government wanted to avoid
This, or what, or what the pharmaceutical companies
but perhaps because there wasn't that much
interest. O sea, simplemente el si tú
You are an industry and you have the
possibility of raising two
products, one can give you a lot of
Money and other things, well, not so much, because
logically you're going to bet on the one that you
It's going to give a lot more money. Not that you go
to torpedo the other with all your might or
Try that, but hey, you're going to put your
interest there and in the world of the of
pharmaceutical medical development uh is
very, very well thought out so that in the end, uh
be something accessible at a
therapeutic, you have to have a
a lot of economic muscle. That is to say,
You can have a drug that works.
superb, for example, the case of MDMA
for the treatment of stress
post-traumatic, which in contexts of use
tremendously effective.
That, no matter how much you can see that it is
very effective, if you don't go through a
clinical trial process
evaluation, all that, if you don't have
So, in the end, what comes out on top?
ahead, right? So, well, the
Psychedelics are coming, but they are
arriving very slowly and they would have arrived
many years earlier, probably if not
That muscle would have been necessary
inexpensive to raise them, right?
It's curious, then, because it seems that
Stimulant drugs, uh, coffee
and depressants too.
And the depressants too.
But that's how it is for me, the way I see it, it's
when you get stimulated, when you take
caffeine, when you take cocaine and everything
That, like your conscience
It doesn't expand; on the contrary, it seems to
You restrict it, and well, that's a
biological process that can be useful in
He will deny that he is tired, that
If he's distracted and such, many times the
Coffee helps you to be more focused. AND
Well, of course, we already talked about it, if
We are talking about people with a deficit in
attention, hyperactivity, with ADHD, ADHD
is the paradigmatic example of how a
stimulants like amphetamine, which are
is considered a dangerous substance, which
In fact, it sells so well in the market
medical as in the illegal market, of
The fact is, it's speed, the speed that in the
street is amphetamine sulfate,
often adulterated,
Unfortunately, but oh well, this is a
to save lives, in quotes, in the
that is, that he has great difficulty in
sitting in a chair for 8 hours
on a computer to work on a
office, would be unable to carry out
This work, because thanks to this
molecule that somehow closes it
and not be constantly distracted by
difficulties with punctuality, order
For example, a person has with
Well, more of a disordered condition?
that the society we live in does not
It is the society in which human beings
It has developed to live.
Caves were an advantage because you were
I've opened up to everything much more, you used to do it
You had more capacity to explore, to
do many more things and so on, but
Of course, when we have changed the
context so much that you have to be 8
hours a day in an office, 8 hours a day
Logically, there are people who don't
I think that's where the function of
The stimulating aspect is facilitating that
The person adapts, right?
I've heard, Anton, that ADHD was like
the people who were in charge of the
because as you have a border of the
attention more scattered, how do you detect the
peligro antes y lo avisas. Therefore,
now we must adapt culturally to having
build, I have to try to build
that for
that it's really not necessary for you
tengas que acudir a la medicación. The
My mication is actually to help you
the way in which it is structured
society, society, you have to deal with it
for eggs. Por ejemplo, el tema del
secondary school and so on. And that's for sure.
Well, I understand that it has a lot there.
sense the use of psychotropic drugs,
especially stimulants, if they help you
to go through that. I mean, that is to say, to me
world. Otra cosa es que tú digas, "No,
I choose, uh, I have TH, so
and I choose to study the most important degree
Studying the world and more than memorizing and
"That's unnecessary." So, that's why I say
que es una condición. Because the
difference, in my opinion, between a
therapeutic approach, because it is a
a situation that in itself is
depending on the context you are in. If you
It causes problems, so it's...
which can be both medication and
even therapy. Pero si tú puedes
you have a problem, for example, if you
You can get him to be a police officer, to be
military, to become an emergency room doctor,
These are professions in which there are high
stress and emergency levels that
They generate an enormous focus on the
brain ADHD. And indeed, those
conditions in which a person with
ADHD, a person without ADHD functions very
bad, which are emergency situations or
under great stress, a person with TH
It soon becomes tremendously effective,
completely.
So, these are professions that are very
good for, that is, they are that are
very well adapted to people with ADHD. So
There, the person doesn't need to take
amphetamine. In other words, if you're in a
ambulance, I am a technician
health emergencies and it is a
profession in which there are a lot of
people with DHD
M
and people go in situations of
emergency, in ambulances and such and
They feel super focused, don't they? And that's it.
something that, for example, uh, no
would require the use of medication in
those contexts. Now, if you have
ADHD and you're, uh, I don't know, a consultant for
office typing code in Excel, phew,
Unless you're truly passionate about it,
which is often the problem with ADHD,
It's that the things you're not passionate about are...
much more complex to manage than ADHD.
Anton, it makes sense that
neurodivergence needs to be treated
because in the end neurodivergence
It means you are not the majority. He
The neurotypical world has been built
around the neurotypical. So, the
Neurodivergence obviously includes that
for you because you're a classist, because
For example, a very similar example is
the example of people who have
that lead them to have rhythms
circadian rhythms different from those of other people
normal. For example, people who
It works great at night.
Yeah?
And it doesn't work in the morning either.
No? What's happening? In other words, society
It practically forces you to have
jobs that run from 9 am to 5 pm
p.m. Almost always. Obviously
There are options you can't work out.
in other courses, but let's say it's
It's difficult to escape that, isn't it?
So, well, there for example I
I understand that those people... well, they
because his body is sleeping,
In other words, it is not society
Most of them are people who get up
I work a lot, and I function much better.
Let it be in the morning, that's fine. Have
also many attention problems.
In fact, I'll tell you that I have one.
ADHD diagnosed since I passed the
COVID. I didn't have this problem before.
attention, well, I had some, well,
We all have problems sometimes
attention, but not at a diagnostic level
that it is considered TH, but yes, it is
that after COVID, COVID made me
has done a lot of damage in the
brain. I've lost a lot of
memory, I've lost a lot of
ability to concentrate to the point that
that I needed to go to a psychiatrist because
I was diagnosed with ADHD and am taking
medication. The thing is, well, I don't know
I take it every day because not everyone...
I do activities that require my
sustained attention, right? For example, in
I haven't had this conversation
taken nothing because to talk, eh, what is it
What I do when I go to podcasts and what
Yes, I have no problem with him needing it
I received a lot of attention and I also feel very
more relaxed and more comfortable when I am
Let's say, right?
at home writing, well, one of them
the three books I have published
I carried it out to this day without, uh, without
medication. Pero bueno, también me da la
feeling that when layers the deficit
also layers of attention
creativity. That is to say,
which are not absolute, that is, not
It's that I say, "No, no, it's not that if I
"I concentrate too much and lose my creativity."
But it is true, and I in that
I think there's quite a bit of sense in that.
evidence, and scientific evidence as well
to support, that closing that focus
Attention, eh, it's very much in favor.
logically to facilitate the tasks
both of the repetitive type and of the
sustained, for example, studying, reading and
Furthermore, but at the same time I believe that
also that closure of attention
a loss of a certain type of
creativity. No, let's not say that the
creativity will not disappear, far from it.
But I do think there is a modulation.
greater dispersion may be associated with
greater creativity and narrowing that focus
attention is also related to
a reduction of that creative capacity.
The thing is, it's true that if you
You reduce that creative capacity, but
You greatly increase the capacity of
work, the ability to execute, that
It can even have a benefit
net at the end. Because? Yeah,
because you can be a very
creative, but if you are very little
functional, that creativity
So it stays there in space, right? AND
The human species is a species that...
It is guided again by what you are capable of
to create or to build. So, you
Your creativity lies solely within you.
your thinking, and that can't be done, no, no
is able to embody it in something, huh
communicable to others, because I believe
that there is a balance in which even
Losing a little creativity, if that's the case
in favor of creating greater functionality
can be very, very beneficial
especially also, that is, if the
you need if you need to run it in
at a certain moment. I've always said that
Creative people begin life
in hard mode when you don't have yet
resources and you lack experience because
tú tienes que ejecutar sí o sí. You begin
Working for someone, then you have
to execute. But when you start to
You have resources and you start to be able to create
your own projects and you start to
use, well, use to work with
people to carry out your
ideas, which is what you're good at,
That's when you've beaten the game and
You're there. And that's why I've brought several
And that happens to him, it happens to him a lot too.
precisamente a la gente con TDH. there is one
a large proportion of people with TH who are
entrepreneurs and who are super people
creative, that is, it is, let's say that
compared to the general population of
But there are also people who...
For example, of people who end up in the
jail. I mean that
for better or for worse, for better or for worse
For better or for worse, eh the
People with ADHD have those
They also have those traps or those
sometimes the impulsiveness that can be
areas,
emotional sensitivity, for example,
Yes, very intensely. Indeed,
That can lead you to [laughs] so much
to have horrible fights, to have fights
Artistic, isn't it? Que es muy que es muy
visible.
The ADHD I brought was like having
a Ferrari, an environment that is a
Ferrari, but it's out of control, it
Panda, not from
important. Yo, por ejemplo, me tomo
that calms me down, because if I have a coffee
estado tomando estimulantes. I have been
the pause. Y ahora, claro, cuando ya
You've had quite a few,
people with then what is called the
no es el esperado. In other words, a
person, for example, with TH who takes
It's a definite feeling, like...
subjective, which is good to know is true
addictions. In fact, it can
has an easier time getting hooked on
in the world. Y es lógico porque al
Also, but well, what are they?
things that nowadays, thanks
We know God much better than before.
In the past, for example, uh, I don't know
I knew why, but hey, people
with attention problems are a
They end up getting hooked on everything, like that, and now
He knows very well why, doesn't he? The the
the deficit of control rather than self-control
that there may be, the fact that you
feel more functional many times with
some stimulant drugs, all that
Well, it makes sense that it ends up taking you there.
That's it, right? But the important thing, I think
In the end, given that ADHD is a
The condition is that you end up finding the
a way to take advantage of that condition to
to improve your world's functionality, to
Improve your creativity, to improve
everything, that is to say, that it is not that it is not the
On the contrary, that is, that you are not a slave,
let's say, of the condition, but rather
find the strengths that you can
to give you, then, that creativity, that
ability to widen the focus considerably, of
Connecting ideas, generating things
new, to move, to have leadership,
Therefore, those things are extremely important and
We should take advantage of that, shouldn't we? But it is
It's true that if it happens to you, because not everyone...
The world can choose the life it leads,
Unfortunately, in the world in which
Unfortunately, they are trapped by
economic conditions or whatever
in the life they are given. So there,
For example, the medication for me has
Makes perfect sense, doesn't it? Is
I mean, he listens, well look, I can't
choosing the context in which I live,
I can modify it to a certain extent,
But hey, I have a very useful tool
powerful stimulants are,
Okay, they're helping me close that light.
attention at will, that's what's very
Well, because if you stop taking the
medication, you immediately return to the
such a state, unless, watch out, because this is something else.
There are also studies that
They point in this direction. The children, eh
that condition was measured. In other words, it has
later on that won't be necessary anymore
medication. O sea, digamos que vuelve
that neurodivergent brain brings it closer
More like a neurotypical brain, right? That
Well, it's something that a lot
which is why many people are starting to
TH. Which is what I don't have
and bring it closer to normal because
As you mentioned, it has some
very interesting strengths.
Everything in life can be a blessing or
curse depending on how you build
your life. The typical example, isn't it, of
They give a test on climbing a tree to
monkey, to the fish, obviously. Of course, that's it.
You spend 8 hours in front of the computer
Doing something, because obviously your life will be affected.
convertirá en una un suplicio. Let's go
Studying law here means working hard.
laws,
But that's why it's important
self-knowledge, to understand which
ideas, such, because ADHD will always be fine, right?
having very strict rules on the part
from someone because of something you say that
That's very true, it's like punctuality, the
to deliver on time, and that's something
que pueden costar mucho al cerebro. the
ability to follow. You when you're not
You're in an optimal state, it's difficult
a lot of work, that is, you need
Do it when you feel like it, right? And
You obviously live in a society where
It can't be like that.
CL you have to be optimal from 9 to C.
From 9 to C. Of course.
That happens to me with Savi, who is the
editor who has been there longer, who has
A horse with ADHD just like me. So
I see him and sometimes he focuses and
I say, "Oh my god, how how can
"Have you been doing this for so many hours?" And
Then there are days when I say, it's just that...
I would send it home because [laughs]
No, it's not necessary, I mean, it won't be possible
do nothing. And that's what society
It does not allow it. Therefore, you take three
coffees, you have your Monster and it has
also makes sense,
No? Y luego que bueno es que hay
many, I mean, it's a real issue that
many hours. [risas] Yo no soy yo no
I am far from being an expert.
In my personal case, as a result of the envelope
Covid has done me a lot of harm in the
head, I've lost my memory, I've lost
Attention, I've even lost fluency
verbal, which I'm not complaining about, I'll continue
being verbally fluent, but not
You know how fluent I used to be,
[clears throat] I mean, I used to say,
I competed in public speaking, in toast
Masters and all that, and now, well, it's just that I...
I get stuck sometimes, I don't remember, I mean,
Well, things that happened to me very, very
abruptly after having Covid,
No? In other words, I'm not saying there's nothing.
of aging in all of this, that
rude. And well, one condition is...
long COVID that many people have gone through
And this is also causing a lot
people in the world today are
starting to have attention problems
which I didn't have before,
But that also happens when scrolling for 22 hours.
followed by that you then screw yourself over
because it is cognitive training
terrible. In other words, we're training
On the contrary, what we should
We need to train, right? In other words, he's watching one
tremendous, tremendous modern, that is
They start shooting like crazy.
very important and that, that, that
training that we are doing as
attention to the constant fixes the brain
The ADHD brain, right? To go from one
Share the idea with others and know how to do it
parallelisms between idea and idea. Host,
scroll and train all the time
and
No. Furthermore, there comes a time when
You don't oversaturate the brain, nor what
that the brain is not very good at
It's the rapid contextual changes.
And when you're exploring, you go from one
video of a girl telling you
uh a fling he had with one and one
historia como super de salseo. A of
Soon a video of a skier who
I was doing some kind of somersault, I don't know what kind of jump.
I don't know how many. [laughter] Suddenly a
video, a fight between some guys who have
stuck to the door. In other words, it is what it is.
so many contextual changes. Is
terrifying for the brain. Suddenly
You're crying and suddenly you're
This must be it. But come on,
I feel very lucky
that social media has
mentally or cerebrally more
to truly mature at the brain level until
You're dying, huh? But come on, this with
What's going to happen, what's going to happen
In fact, if you're already seeing it today
the companies that are manufacturing
Medical professionals manufacture, for example, BS,
because
[snort]
a estar disponible para para TDH. Hills
the night. Entonces, esto como no está
the effect can last too long
depending on the dose you use and
Besides, right? But anyway, it's that
It's a field where you're seeing a
A lot of movement because of the diagnosis
It's skyrocketed these last few years, hasn't it?
Part of it made sense because one
Because it's true that TH was a
disorder that was very
underdiagnosed, but also another
I think part of it has to do with everything
This, that is, with the issue of networks
social and with the theme, I insist, of
COVID, that people are not being
aware of the damage he has done to us
COVID to the brain, that is, from the
the damage it has done at a neuronal level
at the top, there are a lot of
Studies that are pointing to a decline
of measurable intelligence quotient in
population, which is outrageous.
barbarity.
A slight change of subject, but
Going back to the psychological stuff, or
Okay, I have like three things I want
comment. One,
Where are drugs made? No?
oneself, which I think is a topic
interesting.
That's the context variable that you
I mentioned earlier in the triangle of
Cimber, right? Substance, person, context.
I want to go in with that, okay? I mean, that
That's what I most want to discuss, but dude,
I don't know if you saw, you know who Brian is
Johnson, that millionaire, dude,
He recently conducted an experiment with ocidine.
Very interesting,
But he measured it in terms of health, no.
so at a level
that the markers of, that is, all
They were going down, going down in a good way, the
Inflammation was decreasing, I don't know what else.
All this comes from, all this comes from the fact that
that Brian Johnson must have read
quite thoroughly. A study was published
in mice in which they administered a
several markers related to the
aging. Then they saw that the
Silucibin was capable in mice, mind you,
that these things are never
automatically transferable to humans,
But well, many times they are too.
Many times they are. eh they saw
ailocybin made it so that the telomeres of
The mice, right? There are some, and I'm not
an expert in this field, but uh I have
understood that there is a kind of
protections, let's say, that they have
chromosomes that are called telomeres,
I think that basically its length
is highly correlated with the
the aging that occurs in the
asilocybin exposure was even capable of
to make these telomeres
They made them longer, didn't they? In other words,
old people, aren't they? And this is incredible. EITHER
impact on the world of aging
porque es como, wow. In other words, we are
Now it not only has the capacity to
an effect that can be positive even in
the length of these telomeres, but
In addition, the mice that were treated with
celocibimina. So, I was
producing an effect of eh
longevos esos ratones, ¿no? So,
never. Bueno, obviamente no ha morido
terapias antienvejecimiento. And well, to
operate worldwide. That's why
with a person. Pero es interesante
to study, uh, on a large scale, with trials
well planned and all that, and then, well,
He has performed a series of tests on himself
same with Silocivin these last
weeks. He has already included that in
their protocol that every once a month
I think a supermarket is going to be sold
Silocybin trip.
Once a month. Wow.
Yes, I think so. Lo lo
It does not reduce. There is no tolerance for the
silocybin.
Yes, yes. Let's see, in fact, tolerance
With psychedelics, it's a tolerance.
very large. What do I mean by this?
But if you take one day and then the next
The next one will have very little effect on you.
You have to take almost double.
And this is very positive in the sense
which makes it very difficult for people,
Let's say, have a very habitual use
regular, which is never ideal in
No case, right? So, well, with
With silocybin, well yes, you can.
It will produce tolerance,
It will produce a tolerance once, a
The best part of the week, a little bit of
Tolerance might produce it, but
Above all, it would produce a tolerance
important if you take it several times a day
week. That's right, I would stop doing that.
to produce tolerance. And he has done
something that, moreover, like the science of
Psychedelics is very young and there are still
There really should be some to have.
solid conclusions, he has therefore
launched into the mountains and has begun to do
measurements themselves after the
psychedelic experiences and before for
see what changes. And many of those
measurements have not yet been taken
no clinical trial or any
scientific research. So they are
The first is the first time that a being
Humans are measured, for example, I who
I know, the sleep phases before and
things like that. And what he has seen is
that many markers, that in their case
They were hyper-optimized because he carries
supplements, uh, doing all the
anti-aging therapies are being used
a life as totally oriented
únicamente a eso, ¿no? To enhance their
Note that otherwise I wouldn't be able to carry that
lifestyle.
already mega optimized by a super person
Furthermore, there have been metrics that...
perfiles de redes sociales. Very
Interesting because the guy makes a
en en muestras más grandes, ¿no? With
todo de lo que sucede, ¿no? But it is
Interesting, isn't it? y y en su caso la
complejas de abordar, ¿no? Inflammation
corticoides para abordarse. And hey, if
corticosteroids or substances that are much
more problematic and that have much more
Problems? Well, welcome them, right? AND
That is also one of the things
future in the field of psychedelics,
which is the approach or use of the
psychedelics in disorders
Neurological, right? Because until now
We've talked about the psychological aspect, haven't we?
Depression, anxiety, stasis also
Makes sense, doesn't it? than in depression
There are also mental disorders.
a suboptimal functioning, let's say, to
neuronal level. Pero si vamos ya
exclusively to pure disorders
purely neurological, such as
Alzheimer's, as it can be,
neurodegenerative diseases in
general, right? Alzheimer's, Parkinson's,
dementias, as can also be the case, by
For example, accidents
cerebrovasculares, ¿no? A person, by
For example, he has a stroke or suffers a
traumatic phallic and for whatever reason
It may lose the mobility of one
hand. Then he has to submit to
neurorehabilitation so that the brain,
those brain regions that have
lack of blood flow or because of that
because that impact, let's say, has
structural damage has occurred
broken many many connections
brain and so on. Uh, if the
Psychedelics prove to be in humans
capable of increasing that
neuroplasticity, that is, the ability
of the brain that has the ability to reconfigure itself
and also even that capacity to
neurogenesis or synaptogenesis, right?
That ability to produce new
connections or even generate new ones
human, because you know, they have seen in
[snort] that to investigate the
human. Si eso se demuestra, entonces
Psychedelics could also be a
an extremely useful tool in the
neurological. Por ejemplo, una persona
small dose approach
Useful, but perhaps low doses, no
demonstrate that it facilitates that the networks
neurons reconfigure themselves, hey, one
person who is in the process of
onset of a neurodegenerative disorder,
We made their brains more
resilient and can somehow
dampen, especially in phases
Initially, the damage caused by that
trastorno, esa neuroinflamación. I mean,
These substances, but oh well, still
There is much to prove in this regard.
I find it super annoying. There wasn't one.
never thought about it. Sure, that can affect it.
We've completely lost track of time.
[laughs]
No problem.
So, where can people find you? Well, in
damages, right?, what is this approach, this
to use that have a use
inside the head, knowing that it always goes
riesgos, digamos, con con las drogas. AND
drug-related websites and my
No?
nothing,
Thank you. ¿No te da la sensación de que
Choose the perfect one for you? Well
In this case, it will be no different, and the
The algorithm has selected the video
Perfect for you. So click here to
Go to it and don't forget to subscribe. M.